Jean Ritchie and George Pickow collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Subseries 5: Radio shows and album sessions
    - AFC 2008/005: SR075, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-7. BBC Record Library: Jean Ritchie talk on Northern Ireland; Jean talks for BBC North Ireland.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR076, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-8. BBC Record Library: various artists; BBC #1 record library. On reel: BBC1 /BBC Recorded programes [sic] librarys [sic] #1.
      - Gower wassail - Phil Tommer '49 [Langennith?], glam 4' 45"
      - Sweet primroses - Phil Tommer '49 [Langennith?], glam 3' 30"
      - Barbara Allen - 2'28"
      - Gower race ([...] music) - 1' 35"
      - Fair Phoebe and the dark-eyed sailor - 3' 57"
      - The passion and the clerk - 3' 05"
      - The bonnie bunch of roses 3' 12"
      - The Jew's daughter (version of Sir Hugh or the Jews' daughters) 1'22", sung by Mrs. Costello, Birmingham
      - The frog and the mouse (fragment) 0' 40"
      - [weddn'ng?] - long (write me down the powers above) 1 - 1' 25"
      - The handsome cabin boy - 0' 50"
      - My Johnny (version of My Bonny) - 3' 15"
    - AFC 2008/005: SR077, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-9. BBC Record Library: various artists; BBC records.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR078, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      Original ID # SH-10. Book and Author, program; Flamenco; Book of Authors luncheon. Jean. On reel: Jean/Oscar interview. Processor's note: the tape was received as a 5-inch reel and is now housed on a 7-inch reel.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR079, March 1962, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-10a. Ed Cray; interview with Jean Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR080, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-10b. Folk Song Festival: Oscar Brand; Jean Ritchie interview Oscar Brand.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR081, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-11. Folk Song Festival: Oscar Brand; Susan Reed; Jean Ritchie; Oscar; Susan Reed; Jean Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR082, August 16, 1974, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, full track, stereo; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-11a. [NPR label on the front of the tape box]; Folk Festival USA #7432; An Evening with Jean Ritchie; Reel 1 of 4; Open Cue: From Minneapolis; Close Cue: Applause; Length this reel: 29:40; Generation B-1; splices 0; EQ 0; Machine No. 13; RC 2; Eng. Nock/JAS; Source A-1 copy. On reel: Folk Festival USA #7432 /Jean Ritchie, reel 1 of 4 /dub /Libr. [as opposed to Prod. or Air].
    - AFC 2008/005: SR083, August 16, 1974, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, stereo; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-11b. [NPR label on the front of the tape box]; Folk Festival USA #7432; An Evening with Jean Ritchie; Reel 2 of 4; Open Cue: On Some Evenings; Close Cue: NPR Q; Length this reel: 23:40; Generation B-1; splices 0; EQ 0; Machine No. 13; RC 2; Eng. Nock/JAS; Source A-1 copy. On reel: NPR Folk Festival R2 of 4.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR084, August 16, 1974, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, stereo; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-11c. [NPR label on the front of the tape box]; Folk Festival USA #7432; An Evening with Jean Ritchie; Reel 3 of 4; Open Cue: And Now We Return; Close Cue: Applause; Generation B-1; EQ 0; Machine No. 13; RC 2; Eng. Nock; Source A-1 copy. On reel: Folk Festival USA Minneapolis R3 of 4.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR085, August 16, 1974, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, stereo; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-11d. [NPR label on the front of the tape box]; Folk Festival USA #7432; An Evening with Jean Ritchie; Reel 4 of 4; Open Cue: A Special Song; Close Cue: NPR...National Public Radio; Generation B-1; EQ 0; Machine No. 13; RC 2; Eng. Nock; Source A-1 copy. On reel: Folk Festival USA #7432 Reel 4 of 4.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR086, possibly 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-11e. 7 1/2; Jean on Dave Garroway Show.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR087, December 7, 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-12. Folk Song Time; "A Field Trip with Jean Ritchie."
    - AFC 2008/005: SR088, July 16, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-13. Folk Song Time; use last one [sic].
    - AFC 2008/005: SR089, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-13A. Ray Heatherton Show; Jean Ritchie, Oscar, Rock Hudson, Betty Sherry - Ray Heatherton; radio interview; Jean and Oscar Brand on Ray Heatherton.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR090, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-14. The hillbilly record: album rehearsal; on reel: Hillbilly rehearsal.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR091, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-15. Hootenanny at the Limelight - Master #1; Hootenany; R-1.
      - I'll not marry at all - 3:45
      - Rovin gambler - Mike Settle - 11:56
      - Riddle song - 2:27
      - Who's gonna show - 2:33
      - Lonesome valley - 3:31
      - Cindy
    - AFC 2008/005: SR092, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-16. Hootenanny at the Limelight Master #2.
      - Greenback dollar - 3:34
      - Blackeyed Susie - 2:05
      - Midnight Special - 2:35
      - Turtle dove - 2:28
      - Mary don't you weep - 2:43
    - AFC 2008/005: SR093, circa 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-17. Hootenanny at the Limelight.
      - Greenback dollar
      - Lonesome valley
    - AFC 2008/005: SR094, circa 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-18. Hootenanny at the Limelight.
      - Riddle song
      - Cindy
    - AFC 2008/005: SR095, circa 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-19. Hootenanny at the Limelight.
      - Roving gambler
      - Black-eyed Susie
    - AFC 2008/005: SR096, circa 1963, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-20. Hootenanny at the Limelight: Part 2. On reel; Hootenanny pt. 2 and St David Day /radio broadcast.
      - Lord remember me - Reverend Williams
      - Cajun land
      - 61 highway blues - Fred McDowell
    - AFC 2008/005: SR097, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-21. Kentucky Sings show; Jean Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR098, March 1962, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-21a. Legends and Lyrics show; Legends Clynes - Frankie and Johnny; Ellen Stockert; orig 1⁄4" Ranger.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR099, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-22. Look Up and Live (show)
    - AFC 2008/005: SR100, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-23. Music in America show; Spine: Radio WHA Music in America.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR101, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-24. Patchwork #1: Off Broadway show; Spine: Patchwork Off Broadway.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR102, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-25. Patchwork #2: Off Broadway show; Spine: Patchwork Back-up; Back of the tape box: An Anthology of British Blues - John Mayall's Blues Breakers; I'm Your Witch Doctor. J. Mayall's Bluesbreakers - Crusade; Snake Drive - Eric Clapton - Oh Pretty Woman; Ain't Gonna Cry No More - T. S. McPhee - Stand Back Baby; I Tried - Savoy Brown Blues Band - My Time After Awhile; Tribute to Elmore - Eric Clapton - Snowy Wood; I Feel So Good - Jo Ann Kelly - Man of Stone; Telephone Blues - John Mayall's Bluesbreakers - Tears in my Eyes; You Don't Love Me - T.S. McPhee - Driving Sideways; West Coast Idea - Eric Clapton - The Death of J.B. Lenoir; Ain't Seen No Whiskey - Jo Ann Kelly - I Can't Quit You Baby; Flapjacks - Stone's Masonry - Streamline; Cold Blooded Woman - Savoy Brown Blues Band - Me and My Woman; Checking on My Baby. On reel: Patchwork 8T /Backup /heads.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR103, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-26. Pinewoods singing. Back of the tape box: Children's Play Party. On reel: Pinewood /duplicate / alternative.
      - Pete Sawyer tells about telling stories
      - Trot a little horse (fragment) - Jean Ritchie and Kid Steven
      - Ride a little Horsie (fragment) - Jean Ritchie and Kid Steven
      - Roving gambler - Hedy West
      - Poor little lost baby - Hedy West
      - Jean Ritchie intro
      - Frog went a-courting (tape [...] at start) - Seamus Ennis
      - Unidentified song - Seamus Ennis
      - Dancing children in the knee - Seamus Ennis
    - AFC 2008/005: SR104, October 26, 1973, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-27. Pinewoods Tribute to Jean Ritchie #1. Back of the tape box: JR - Pinewoods tribute.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR105, October 26, 1973, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 4 track, stereo; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-28. Pinewoods Tribute to Jean Ritchie #2. Back of the tape box: [Collegium Sound Systems sticker]; Ampex 406; both direct; no Dolby; Tribute to Jean Ritchie; 1 of 2.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR106, circa 1962, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-29. Precious memories: album rehearsal. On reel: Hillbilly rehearsal.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR107, circa 1959, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-29a. The Ritchie family of Kentucky (Folkways).
    - AFC 2008/005: SR108, circa 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-30. ["Marching across the green grass"?]. Spine: Children Folkways.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR109, circa 1968, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-31. ["Marching across the green grass" ?]; album rehearsal. Spine: Slow Children. Back of the tape box: Slow children record (too fast).
      - Boston
      - Train a-comin - Jon Pickow and Jean Ritchie
      - Skin and bones
      - Old bald eagle - Jean and dulcimer
    - AFC 2008/005: SR110, circa 1965, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-32. Time for singing album.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR111, circa 1965, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-33. Spine: Time for singing rehearsal. Back of the tape box: no sync.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR112, March 18, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-34. Today Show: Jean Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR113, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-35. Spine: Voice of America - Jean Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR114, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-36. Spine: Voice of America; Play Party. On reel: A time for singing /Warner Bros.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR115, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-37. Spine: Wandering Five.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR116, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-38. Wandering Five rehearsal. Spine: Wandering Five. Back of the tape box: George Pickow - test. On reel: rehearsal Wandering Five.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR117, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-39. Spine: Welcome Travelers.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR118, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-40. Spine: Woman-Made Music; J.R. Back of the tape box: [Educational Communications Board sticker]; Woman Made Music: Jean Ritchie; Aired Sunday, Jan. 4, 11 PM.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR119, December 27, 1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-41. Side panel: Big Blackboard; WCAU - TV (Jean: 12/27/58). On reel: Big Blackboard [program]/12/27/58 [air date] / WCAU-TV /Philadelphia.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR120, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, one-half track, stereo; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-41a. WHA Simply Folk: Jean Ritchie #1. Spine: Jean Ritchie Concert at Madison R One. Back of the tape box: [Wisconsin Public Radio sticker]; series: Simply Folk; Title: Jean Ritchie; number one of two; note: because of the length of the first set, this set is on 1 mil tape!; tail out; dub; eng. Ebme; Mach. ATR-700.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR121, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-41b. WHA Simply Folk: Jean Ritchie #2. Spine: Jean Ritchie Concert at Madison R Two. Back of the tape box: [Wisconsin Public Radio sticker]; series: Simply Folk; Title: Jean Ritchie; 7 1/2; Stereo; 1⁄2 track; number two of two; tail out; dub; eng. Ebme; Mach. ATR-700.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR122, April 24, 1974, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, stereo; 7 in. master
      Folk Music and Bernstein; Jean Ritchie Part 1. [National Public Radio sticker]; series: Folk music and Bernstein; n. 7503; Jean Ritchie Pt. III; Open cue: Program Theme; Close Cue: NPR system cue; length this reel: 60:26; instructions: ID break at 31:05 (10 seconds); on reel: Jean Ritchie, Part 1 /length 60:55 /reel 1 of 1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR123, April 24, 1974, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, stereo; 7 in. master
      Folk Music and Bernstein; Jean Ritchie Part 2. [National Public Radio sticker]; series: Folk Music and Bernstein; n. 7504; Jean Ritchie Pt. IV; Open cue: Program Theme; Close Cue: NPR system cue; length this reel: 58:51; Generation: Master; Splices: lots; instructions: ID break at 30:55 (10 seconds). On reel: Jean Ritchie, Part __ / reel 1 of 1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR124, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-42. WHYY Television: Jean Ritchie. Spine: TV spots for WHYY.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR125, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-43. WNYC Radio: Jean Ritchie. On container: Jean Ritchie in NY. On reel: Jean's WNYC /Begin - has recorder ....
    - AFC 2008/005: SR126, October 31, 1963, November 1971, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, one-half track, mono; 7 in.
      Original ID # SH-44. WYSO Radio: Jean Ritchie. Spine: Jean Ritchie-WYSO; Pt. 1 of 3 10/31/63; 12M-2:35PM THU. Back of the tape box: [WYSO Sticker]; Reel 1 of 1 (both sides); Dub; 53 min.; Part I and II - Jean Ritchie program; The Cumberland mountain childhood of Jean Ritchie; producer Judith Supunich; air dates: several; date recorded: 11/71.
  - Subseries 6: Ritchie family
    - AFC 2008/005: SR127, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-1. Ritchie Family. Hall, Henry (church songs). Recorded Viper; Henry Hall's Church - Songs; Cross That Lonely River; Eastern Gate; Bad timing on beginnings of verses; first take - K forgets words; Swapping song Kitty and Dule. On the reel: recorded Viper.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR128, August 24, 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-2. Hall Reunion #1. On the reel: Hall reunion. Processor's note: this is probably a recording of a Hall family reunion; Jean's mother's maiden name was Hall.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR129, August 24, 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-3. Hall Reunion #2. Hall Reunion; Reel 1; Includes songs by Kelly, Mallie, Edna and Jean Ritchie. See processor's note for SR128.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR130, August 24, 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-4. Hall Reunion #3. On the reel: Hall reunion. See processor's note for SR128.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR131, July 28, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-5. Kermiet Children (of Pauline Ritchie and Paul Kermiet). Charlie - by children; Rock County. On the reel: Kermiet children.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR132, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-6. Ritchie, Abigail #1. On the reel: Ma Ritchie, Abigail.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR133, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      Original ID # RF-7. Ritchie, Abigail #2. Mom "somebody with dulcimer"; "Fly Around"; Abby Mom Ritchie. Processor's note: the tape was received as a 5-inch reel and is now housed on a 7-inch reel.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR134, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-8. Ritchie, Abigail #3. Scene 1, Take 1, Sound 1 - Ritchie Family; There was a little family; Amazing grace with Jeannie - good; good train sound. On the reel: Mom Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR135, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-9. Ritchie, Edna #1. Golden Little. On the reel: Edna II.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR136, January 3, 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips,; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-10. Ritchie, Edna #2. Dub; dubbed at Lou Gordon's apt by Artie [Leach]. On the reel: Edna Ritchie (good dub) /lots blank tape at beginning.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR137, December 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      Original ID # RF-11. Ritchie, Edna #3 (at Berea). Inside the box lid: Tape made at Berea, Christmas, 1956, by Bob Black of Bloomington, Ind. I forgot what I sang! Keep for me. Processor's note: the tape was received as a 5-inch reel and is now housed on a 7-inch reel.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR138, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-12. Ritchie, Edna #4 (music class at Dilce Combs School, Jeff, Kentucky). On the reel: Edna Ritchie /Dilce Combs / music class
    - AFC 2008/005: SR139, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips and 15 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-12a. Ritchie, Edna #5.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR140, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-12b. Ritchie, Edna #6.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR141, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-13. Ritchie, Edna with Jean Ritchie and Hally Wood. Jean Edna and Hally Wood Gordon - at Viper. On the reel: Jean Ritchie /Edna Ritchie /Hally /about 2/5 empty.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR142, January 1965, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-14. Ritchie, Isom (Grandpa) #1. Grandpa Isom Ritchie; Stories on Side 1 and 2; end of Side 2 - Marshall Smith picking the banjo; Jan. 7 [?0], 1965.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR143, circa January 1965, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-15. Ritchie, Isom (Grandpa) #2. Jean, Edna, Mom at Viper - front; Isom Ritchie - Lick Branch - tales; Rec. by Lauren [Kramer].
    - AFC 2008/005: SR144, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-16. Uncle Jason Ritchie #1. Green grow rushes; My love is like a red red rose; all "Sweet Jane" of Mom singing " a few more years still." On the reel: Jason Ritchie #1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR145, Summer 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-17. Uncle Jason Ritchie #2. Uncle Jason, Baby, Susan, etc; house - summer '54; Bob Coltman, from Pennsylvania; "Here you come two by two" - Uncle Jason; "Poor old chimney sweeper" - Uncle Jason, two takes; snatches of songs sung by Susan. Baby cries, etc; "In Nottamun Town" - Bob Coltman; "It's all account of somebody" - Bob Coltman and banjo. On the reel: Uncle Jason Baby and Boy Sampler 54.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR146, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      Original ID # RF-18. Uncle Jason Ritchie #3. Processor's note: the tape was received as a 5-inch reel and is now housed on a 7-inch reel.
      - Uncle Jason and home folks
      - Discussion of Kelly [Kranky] and play songs
      - Will you love me when I'm old - Jason
      - Locks and bolts
      - Cherry tree carol
      - When they go [courtin] - Jason
      - Dad comments on this song
      - Merry golden tree - Jason
    - AFC 2008/005: SR147, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-19. Uncle Jason Ritchie #4. Jean and Uncle Jason talking.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR148, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-20. Uncle Jason Ritchie #5.
      - Jason Ritchie
      - Woody Guthrie on Oscar Brand show [Folk Song Festival]
      - Huddie Leadbetter
      - Jason Ritchie [Boxhs] of the Ohio
      - Who will shoe my bonny feet?
      - Robin Hood
      - Marching to set Cuba free
      - The day I left my home
      - The day I left my home - Woody Guthrie
      - Good morning Mr. railroad man
      - Foggy mountain top
      - I ride on old paint
    - AFC 2008/005: SR149, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-21. Uncle Jason Ritchie #6. Miller and his three sons - complete. On the reel: Jason.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR150, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-21a. Uncle Jason Ritchie #7. Talk intro. Jean Ritchie; visit to Jason Ritchie; Little Musgrave.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR151, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-21b. Uncle Jason Ritchie #8.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR152, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-22. Aunt Mary Ritchie (married Felix Ritchie). Practice tapes for Voice of America program; openings - closings; Aunt Mary Ritchie - songs, tales; Jean - songs (tunes) for Al Fossner for book; After Skin and bones; Lazy John; Pretty far [???]. On the reel: original tape of Aunt Mary /very brittle.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR153, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips and 15 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-23. Aunt Polly Ritchie (married Edward Pearl, then went back to maiden name after [divorce]).
      - Somebody (acc. by dulcimer - Jean)
      - Derby ram; dub list 2 set to 7 1/2 ips
      - Aunt Polly talking to Dad
      - I am a little scholar
      - Darby ram - mother - churn scene begins blue - ends white
    - AFC 2008/005: SR154, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-24. Una Ritchie (sister) #1 (married Thomas Yahkub). Processor's note: the tape was received as a 5-inch reel and is now housed on a 7-inch reel.
      - John Henry Sally Ann
      - Well met
      - Peg an awl
      - Old shoe boots and leggings
      - Old lord by the North Sea
      - Shady grove
    - AFC 2008/005: SR155, January 28, 1954, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-25. Una Ritchie (sister) #2 (married Thomas Yahkub). Una Ritchie Yahkub. On the reel: Una Ritchie /Jan 28 1954 / N.Y.
      - Mommy told me to open the gate - two false starts
      - The old gray mare - two bad starts, no good takes
      - Pretty Polly - one false start, then complete, good long version
      - Bow your bend to me - two false starts. Last few verses repeated because of something.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR156, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-26. Family concert reunion - Colorado.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR157, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-27. Family reunion concert - Colorado.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR158, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-28. Ritchie family songs #1.
      - Brightest and best - whole family
      - Pretty Saro - Pauline, Edna, and Jean
      - Aunt Rhody - Edna and Jean - two dulcimers
    - AFC 2008/005: SR159, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips.; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-29. Ritchie Family #2. On the reel: Reel II / Ritchie Family Reel 1_2.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR160, circa 1965, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-30. Viper Kentucky Ritchies. Tape box spine: Jean, Ed, Floyd, Mallie, Kit, Mom, Jon Viper '65; Kitty, Edna, Floyd, Mallie, Jean.
      - Sweet May morning - Edna and Floyd
      - Pretty little rockless boy - Edna and Floyd
      - Riddle song harmony in fourth - Edna and Floyd
      - Milder to [Malder] - Johnny, Jean
      - Young man wouldn't raise corn - Ed and Jean unaccompanied
      - Young man wouldn't raise corn - Ed and Jean unaccompanied retake
      - John Riley - Ed, Jean, Kitty, Mallie; Mallie sings one verse, Kitty sings one verse, Mom sings one verse, Darby ram then whole song
      - Aunt Rhodie - Ed and Floyd - unaccompanied
      - Sweet May morning - ?
      - Front porch scene
      - Darby ram - mother churning no good beginning blue end white
    - AFC 2008/005: SR161, circa December 1957, January 1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-31. Kentucky Ritchie NY. On the reel: Kentucky Ritchies home.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR162, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Original ID # RF-32. Ritchie family [...] Pretty Saro, etc. No. 1 Monday; Pretty Saro; Joe Bowers; Pa Ritchie; Mallie and Edna; Old Tyler; Edna; Ma Ritchie; I am somebody's darlin'.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR163, December 30, 1953, July 1955, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.